Inventory to the Nasser Sharify Papers, 1902-1993 (Bulk 1950-1989)
Hoover Institution Archives
- P- Research projects file, 1955-1988 (Box 68-73)
  - P-3. Research materials for survey of library collections of State University of New York (SUNY) system, 1967 (Folder 69: 2-6)
  - P-4. Research materials for paper presented at IFLA conference (Brussels), 1977 (Folder 69-70)
    - Paper, "The Belt Around the Globe: Observations and Remarks on Education for Librarianship in the Middle East,", 1977 (Folder 69: 7)
    - Research materials, 1958-1977 (Folder 70)
      - Egypt, United Arab Republic of, 1974 (Folder 70: 1)
      - Iran, 1976-1977 (Folder 70: 2-8)
      - Iraq, 1958 (Folder 70: 9)
      - Israel, 1976-1977 (Folder 70: 10-15)
      - Jordan, 1973-1974 (Folder 70: 16-17)
      - Kuwait, 1975 (Folder 70: 18)
      - Lebanon, 1973-1977 (Folder 70: 19-20)
      - Middle East, 1967-1975 (Folder 70: 21)
      - Saudi Arabia, 1974-1977 (Folder 70: 22-23)
      - Turkey, 1965-1977 (Folder 70: 24-25)
  - P-5. Paper presented at IFLA conference (Budapest), "Beyond the National Frontiers" and related correspondence, 1974 (Folder 70: 26)
  - P-6. Research materials for paper presented to Library of Congress on Persian transliteration, 1956 (Folder 70: 27)
  - P-7. Research materials for the creation of Pratt's new School of Computer, Information and Library Sciences, 1985-1987 (Folder 71-73)
    - General, 1984-1985 (Folder 71: 1)
    - ALA visit, 1984-1985 (Folder 71: 2-3)
    - ALISE, 1985 (Folder 71: 4)
    - Comp. search, 1985 (Folder 71: 5)
    - Curriculum-General information, 1977 (Folder 71: 6)
    - Education, 1982-1984 (Folder 71: 7)
    - Market, 1984-1985 (Folder 71: 8)
    - Outline, 1985 (Folder 71: 9)
    - Proposal, 1984 (Folder 71: 10)
    - Undergraduate curricula interactions, circa 1985 (Folder 71: 11)
    - Universities (Folder 71-72)
      - Berkeley, University of California, 1979 (Folder 71: 12)
      - Drexel University, 1984-1985 (Folder 72: 1-2)
      - Louisiana State University, 1984-1985 (Folder 72: 3)
      - Pittsburgh, University of, 1984-1985 (Folder 72: 4-5)
      - Pratt University, 1984-1985 (Folder 72: 6-8)
      - Rutgers, undated (Folder 72: 9)
      - Syracuse University, 1984-1986 (Folder 72: 10-14)
      - Tennessee, Knoxville, University of, 1984 (Folder 72: 15)
    - Miscellaneous research materials regarding post-graduate library education, 1970-1985 (Folder 73: 1-5)
  - P-8. Pratt Institute Research Council materials, 1972-1987 (Folder 73: 6)
- Q- Central Treaty Organization (CENTO) file, 1960-1968 (Box 74-76, 103)
  Relates to book development projects in Turkey, Pakistan, and Iran.
  - Q-2. Reports on book production in Iran, Pakistan, and Turkey, vols. I-IV, 1966 (Folder 74: 1)
  - Q-2. Related studies, 1960-1968 (Folder 74: 2-11)
  - Q-4. Financial records, 1966 (Folder 74: 12-13)
  - Q-5. Contracts, 1966 (Folder 75: 1)
  - Q-6. Briefing and debriefing conferences, Washington, D.C., 1966 (Folder 75: 2-4)
  - Q-7. Mission documents and correspondence, 1964-1968 (Folder 75: 5-15)
    Includes materials related to libraries in Iran and administrative correspondence regarding the CENTO mission
  - Q-7. Mission documents and correspondence, 1964-1968 (Contd.) (Folder 76: 1-4)
    Includes correspondence related to Turkey and Pakistan and correspondence of George Sadler
- R- Brooklyn Public Library newsletters, minutes, and correspondence, 1968-1975 (Folder 76: 5-11)
- S- Pratt Institute School of Computer, Information and Library Sciences file, 1987 (Folder 76: 12)
  Regarding appointment of Nasser Sharify as Distinguished Professor and Dean Emeritus
- T- Conferences, institutes, and workshops materials, 1963-1988 (Box 78-82, 101-102)
  Includes conference papers, administrative documents, speaker's agenda, and correspondence.
  - T-1. International Library Manpower (ILMP) materials relating to education and placement in North America and an international conference held in Detroit, 1970 (Folder 78-80:)
    Includes reports and fact sheets for library services in developing and developed countries
  - T-2. Institute on International Comparative Librarianship, 1965 (Folder 80:)
    Includes 4 7-inch open reel tapes of conference proceedings
  - T-3. "Mexico on Microfilm" conference, 1967 (Folder 80:)
  - T-4. International Conference on Organization and Control of Information for Islamic Research, Purdue University, Indiana, 1982 September 3-5 (Folder 81: 1-4)
  - T-5. Conference on Visiting Foreign Librarians in the United States, held by ILLRIS, SUNY,1967 March 30-31 (Folder 81: 5)
  - T-6. Conference on International Responsibilities of College and University Libraries, ILLRIS, SUNY, 1967 October 2-4 (Folder 81: 6)
  - T-7. "Consultation in Third World Countries: Prospects, Procedures, Planning, ASIS pre-conference seminar, 1984 October (Folder 82: 1-4)
- A (Contd.)- Pahlavi National Library file, 1975-1976 (Box 83-95)
  - Financial records, 1975-1976 (Folder 83-95)
    Includes paid invoices, receipts, and taxes
- Incremental materials received June 1989 (Folder 95)
  - Pratt Institute press release relating to Sharify receiving International Gold Medal and brochure regarding the Nasser Sharify Lecture Series, 1989 May-June (Folder 95)
- Incremental materials received in 1998, 1902-1993 (Bulk 1950-1989) (Box 96-102)
  Includes reports, brochures, correspondence, newsletters, minutes, writings, research materials, and sound recording
  - A (Contd.)- Pahlavi National Library file (Folder 96)
    - A-1. Press, national and international, 1976 (Folder 96: 1)
    - A-1/1. Comments by other professionals, 1975-1976 (Folder 96: 2)
    - A-2. Articles and brochures about PNL, 1976-1977 (Folder 96: 3)
    - A-3/1. Draft of final report, 1976 (Folder 96: 4)
    - A-4. Briefing documents, 1975 (Folder 96: 5)
    - A-6. Consultants biographical data, 1976 (Folder 96: 6)
    - A-7. Financial documents, 1975-1978 (Folder 96: 7)
    - A-8. Contracts, 1977 (Folder 96: 8)
    - A-9. Correspondence, 1974-1978 (Folder 96: 9)
    - A-9/1. Correspondence to consultants, 1975-1978 (Folder 96: 10)
    - A-10. Organziational chart and slides, circa 1976 (Folder 96: 11)
    - A-11. Implementation plan, 1975-1977 (Folder 96: 12)
    - A-12. Chairman's progress and administrative reports, 1976 (Folder 96: 13)
    - A-15. Architectural programs, designs, and international architecture competition papers, 1976 (Folder 96: 14)
    - A-16. Correspondence regarding publication of final report, 1976 (Folder 96: 15)
  - D (Contd.)- Reza Shah Kabir University file (Folder 97)
    - D-1. Site and academic planning reports for library, 1976 (Folder 97: 1)
    - D-2. Planning report proposal for library instruction and research, 1976 (Folder 97: 2)
    - D-3. Correspondence, 1976 (Folder 97: 3)
    - D-4. Consultants, 1976 (Folder 97: 4)
    - D-5. Final report, 1976 (Folder 97: 5)
    - D-6. Budget, 1976 (Folder 97: 6)
    - D-6. Contract, 1976 (Folder 97: 7)
    - D-6. Briefing documents for Pahlavi National Library, 1975 (Folder 97: 8)
  - E (Contd.)- Farah Pahlavi University file (Folder 97:)
    - E-1. Plans and correspondence, 1977 (Folder 97: 9)
  - F (Contd.)- Centre National de Documentation (C.N.D.) file (Folder 97:)
    - F-4. Brochures and reports, 1986-1988 (Folder 97: 10)
      In French and Arabic
  - G (Contd.)- Meknes University file (Folder 97:)
    - G-1. Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Folder 97: 11)
  - H (Contd.)- Ecole des Sciences de l'Information file (Folder 97)
    - H-2. Curriculum materials, 1989 (Folder 97: 12)
    - H-6. Correspondence, 1974 (Folder 97: 13)
  - K (Contd.)-Offices Held in Professional Associations file (Folder 98)
    - K-4/3/1. ALA/LED Committee on Equivalencies and Reciprocity, 1970 (Folder 98: 1)
    - K-4/5. ALA/LED International Relations Roundtable correspondence, 1967-1970 (Folder 98: 2)
    - K-8. International Federation for Documentation (FID) delegate to Tokyo, travel itineraries and correspondence, 1967 (Folder 98: 3)
    - K-10. New York Library Association-Library Education Section newsletters and correspondence, 1970-1975 (Folder 98: 4)
    - K-11. New York School Librarian's Association correspondence, 1964-1971 (Folder 98: 5)
    - K-12. New York Social Responsibilities Roundtable, 1971 (Folder 98: 6)
    - K-13. Music Library Association-New York Chapter minutes and correspondence, 1966-1967 (Folder 98: 7)
    - K-14. New York Library Association bulletins and correspondence, 1967-1974 (Folder 98: 8)
  - L (Contd.)- SUNY (State University of New York) Department of International Studies and World Affairs file (Folder 98)
    - L-1. General, 1981 (Folder 98: 9)
    - L-2. ILLRIS administrative documents, 1966-1968 (Folder 98: 10)
  - M (Contd.)-Pratt Institute Graduate School of Library and Information Science file (Folder 99)
    - M-2. Plans for the future, Circa 1983 (Folder 99: 1)
    - M-3. Essay by Sharify about program, undated (Folder 99: 2)
    - M-4. Center for International Librarianship Studies overview, 1969 (Folder 99: 3)
  - N (Contd.)- UNESCO file (Folder 99)
    - N-1. Minutes and correspondence regarding educational documentation centers, 1959-1960 (Folder 99: 4)
    - N-2. UNESCO mission to Iran correspondence, 1960 (Folder 99: 5)
    - N-3. Reading Materials Project correspondence, 1959 (Folder 99: 6)
    - N-4. Mission to Indonesia, 1956 (Folder 99: 7)
    - N-5. Mission to Ceylon, undated (Folder 99: 8)
    - N-6. Tropical Africa Project reports and fact sheets, 1960 (Folder 99: 9)
    - N-7. Seminars on Arab states, 1960 (Folder 99: 10)
  - O (Contd.)- University of Pittsburgh file (Folder 99)
    - O-2. International Library Information Center (ILIC) proposal, 1965 (Folder 99: 11)
  - P (Contd.)- Research Projects file (Folder 99)
    - P-2. Libraries in Afghanistan, undated (Folder 99: 12)
    - P-3. SUNY collection survey, undated (Folder 99: 13)
    - P-6. Library of Congress Persian transliteration research materials and project proposal, 1955-1958 (Folder 99: 14-15)
    - P-9. Mary Wright Plummer research materials, 1902-1975 (Folder 100: 1-17)
      Includes original works by Plummer including Hints for Small Libraries (1902) and Training for Librarianship (1923)
    - P-10. Encyclopedia of Library and Information Science, research articles on Middle Eastern countries, 1966-1968 (Folder 100: 18)
    - P-11. Research materials for Deafness, Speech, and Hearing Index, 1964 (Folder 100: 19)
  - Q (Contd.)- Central Treaty Organization (CENTO) file (Folder 100)
    - Q-1. Press, national and international, 1966 (Folder 100: 20)
  - R (Contd.)- Brooklyn Public Library file (Folder 100)
    - R-1. Minutes of meetings and reports, 1979 (Folder 100: 21)
  - T (Contd.)- Conferences, Institutes, and Workshop materials (Folder 101-102)
    - T-2. Institute on International Librarianship, Pittsburgh, 1965 June (Folder 101: 1)
      Includes one 7-inch open reel tape
    - T-3. "Mexico on Microfilm" conference materials, 1967 October (Folder 101: 2)
      Includes one 7-inch open reel
    - T-5. Conference on visiting foreign libraries in the United States, 1967 (Folder 101: 3)
    - T-6. Conference on International Responsibilities of College and University Libraries, 1965-1968 (Folder 101: 4)
    - T-7. Consultations in Third World Countries: Prospects, Procedures, Planning, 1984 (Folder 101: 5)
    - T-8. International Cataloging Conference, London and Paris, 1959-1961 (Folder 101: 6)
    - T-9. SUNY Faculty Assembly, Syracuse, 1967 (Folder 101: 7)
    - T-10. Comparative Education Conference, SUNY, 1967 (Folder 101: 8)
    - T-11. Comparative Education Society, Albany, program, 1968 (Folder 101: 9)
    - T-12. International Federation of Library Associations and Institutions (IFLA) conference, Belgium, 1977 (Folder 101: 10)
      Includes paper delivered by Nasser Sharify and related correspondence
    - T-13. CENTO Seminar on Library Development, Ankara, 1961-1962 (Folder 101: 11)
    - T-13. UNESCO Seminar on Library Development in Arabic Speaking Countries, Beirut, 1959 (Folder 101: 12)
    - T-15. Special Libraries Association Institute for Foreign Librarians, 1956 (Folder 102: 1)
    - T-16. The Role of the University in the Quest for Peace, American and Canadian conference, 1967 (Folder 102: 2)
    - T-17. Nasser Sharify Lecture series at Pratt University, brochure, 1988 (Folder 102: 3)
    - T-18. SLA Global Information Access, Anaheim, 1987 (Folder 102: 4)
    - T-19. International Conference on Library Education, Illinois, 1968 (Folder 102: 5)
    - T-20. Columbia University Seminar, 1993 (Folder 102: 6)
    - T-21. UNESCO Meeting of Educational Publishers, Geneva, 1961 (Folder 102: 7)
    - T-22. Government Advisory Committee on International Book and Library Programs, minutes, 1977 (Folder 102: 8)
  - U- Tehran University, Research Center for Sciences, draft report, 1960s (Folder 102: 9)
  - V- Burundi National Center for Documentation materials, 1972-1976 (Folder 102: 10)
  - W- Iranian Library Association consititution, 1960 (Folder 102: 11)
  - X- A World Building on Education, Learning, and Technology (B.E.L.T., Inc.), 1977 (Folder 102: 12-13)
  - Y- Library Education Program of Imperial Medical Center of Iran, 1977-1978 (Folder 102: 14)
  - Z-1. Kuwait Institute for Scientific Research, 1981 (Folder 102: 15)
  - Z-2. Public Library Development, 1981-1982 (Folder 102: 16)
  - AA- Maurice Tauber Foundation, 1983 (Folder 102: 17)
  - BB- "Proposal for the Establishment of an Institute of Librarianship," Cairo, Egypt, 1950 (Folder 102: 18)
- Incremental materials received in 2012, 1961-1985 (Box 103)
  Includes brochures, newsletters, reports, correspondence, briefing documents, minutes, and notes
  - A (Contd.)- Pahlavi National Library file (Folder 103:)
    - A-2. Brochure about the PNL, 1976 (Folder 103: 1)
    - A-4. Set of minutes and highlight notes from briefing seminar, 1975 (Folder 103: 2-3)
    - A-4. Briefing documents prepared by Iranian consultants, vols. 1-2, 1975 (Folder 103: 4-7)
  - J-1 (Contd.). IFLA. "Beyond the National Frontiers: International Dimention of Changing Library Education for a Changing World," by Nasser Sharify, circa 1974 (Folder 103: 8)
  - J-6 (Contd.). American Society for Information Science (ASIS). Notes on consultation in third world countries, 1985 (Folder 103: 8)
  - K-6 (Contd.). Bulletin (1977) and materials from International Conference on Cataloging Principles, 1961 (Folder 103: 9)
  - O-2 (Contd.). University of Pittsburgh, International Library and Information Center materials, 1965-1966 (Folder 103: 10)
  - Q-1 (Contd.). CENTO press clippings relating to book survey and Pakistan library, 1966 (Folder 103: 11)